{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Non bacterial ropiness or sliminess in milk and milk products may be due to the", "opta": "stringiness caused by mastitis and in particular by fibrin and leucocytes from the cow's blood.", "optb": "sliminess resulting from the thickness of the cream", "optc": "stringiness due to thin films of casein or lactalbumin during cooling", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The yoghurt is made from", "opta": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optb": "Streptococcus thermophilus", "optc": "S. cremoris", "optd": "mixed culture of (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cheese cancer of Swiss and similar cheese is caused by", "opta": "Oospora Crustacea", "optb": "Oospora caseovorans", "optc": "Oospora aurianticum", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Swelling of the can is caused primarily by", "opta": "gas forming, anaerobic spore formers", "optb": "gas forming, aerobic spore formers", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bulgarian butter milk is made with the help of", "opta": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optb": "Streptococcus lactis", "optc": "Streptococcus thermophilus", "optd": "S. cremoris", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ropiness caused by Enterobacter usually is", "opta": "worse at the middle of the milk", "optb": "worse at the bottom of the milk", "optc": "worse near the top of the milk", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A brown color in milk may result from", "opta": "Pseudomonas putrefaciens", "optb": "the enzymatic oxidation of tyrosine by P. fluorescens", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "S. marcescens", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following species of Clostridium is responsible for formation of dark green to black colours in cheese?", "opta": "Clostridium tyrobutyricum", "optb": "Clostridium sporogenes", "optc": "Clostridium herbarum", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Certain strains of  Streptococcus lactis var. maltigenes may produce", "opta": "bitter flavor", "optb": "acid flavor", "optc": "burnt or caramel flavor", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The acidity may be described as \"aromatic\" when", "opta": "Lactic streptococci and aroma forming Leuconostoc species are growing together", "optb": "Streptococcus lactis and other lactis are growing together", "optc": "appreciable amounts of volatile fatty acids are produced by Coliform bacteria", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Surface taint in butter which is blamed on Pseudomonas putrefaciens is also called as", "opta": "rabbito", "optb": "putridity", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cheese with too low an acidity because of the addition of cream or the failure of the starter often is made gelatinous or slimy by", "opta": "Pseudomonas", "optb": "P. fragi", "optc": "Alcaligenes metalcaligenes", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pseudomonas syncyanea produces a", "opta": "bluish gray to brownish color in milk in its pure form", "optb": "brownish color to bluish gray in milk in its pure form", "optc": "gray to brownish color in milk", "optd": "yellow color in milk", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pseudomonas nigrifaciens in mildly salted butter may cause", "opta": "black smudge", "optb": "greenish areas", "optc": "pink color", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Esters like flavors in butter are resulted from the action of", "opta": "P. mephitica", "optb": "Aeromonas hydrophila", "optc": "P. fragi", "optd": "Pseudomonas synxantha", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Acidophilus milk which is used for its therapeutic properties in intestinal disorders requires for its manufacture a pure culture of", "opta": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optb": "Streptococcus thermophilics", "optc": "Lactobacillus acidophilus", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A yellow color in the creamy layer of milk may be caused by", "opta": "Pseudomonas synxantha", "optb": "Pseudomonas syncyanea", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "S. marcescens", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alkaline reaction in milk is caused by the alkali formers bacteria as", "opta": "Pseudomonas fluorescens", "optb": "A. viscolactis", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial ropiness in milk is caused by", "opta": "slimy capsular material from the cells usually gums or mucins", "optb": "slimy capsular material from the cells usually proteins", "optc": "slimy capsular material from the cells usually lipids", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fishiness in butter is caused by", "opta": "Aeromonas hydrophila", "optb": "Pseudomonas synxantha", "optc": "Pseudomonas syncyanea", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chief type of spoilage in sweetened condensed milk may be", "opta": "gas formation by sucrose fermenting yeasts", "optb": "thickening caused by micrococci", "optc": "mold colonies growing on the surface", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}